(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-28T16:18:47.384400",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
離れないで
Don't leave me...
ここに宣言します サプライズをいずる
We hereby declare to produce a surprise!
ひとつ 病める時も
Whether in sickness,
すこやかなるときも
or in health,
ずっと 愛を 歌い続けることを ここに 誓います
I swear here to keep singing of love forever.
豊かとか富むとか ダンスももっと追求します
Whether rich or poor, I will pursue dancing even more,
みいつまでも 推してもらえる アイドルになってみせます 洋々な未来も
and show you I can be an idol you'll support forever into a bright future.
私が照らすんだ それでも 落ち込んじゃう時は 思い出しているよ みんなのその笑顔 その声
I will illuminate it. Even when I feel down, I remember everyone's smiles and voices.
ハッピーラッキーセブン
Happy, lucky, seven!
革命起こせ どんな時でも この先ずっと 一緒だよね 約束
Spark a revolution no matter what; we'll be together forever from now on, I promise.
ほらね 笑う門にはそら来たる ハッピーバースデー 毎日が ほら 終始ウェスデー ラッキーデイ
Look, fortune smiles upon Sora. Happy birthday, every day is truly a lucky Wednesday!
生まれ変わっても 迷わずに 君だけの アイドルに なるよ
Even if I'm reborn, without hesitation, I'll become your one and only idol.
何度も 見つけてね サプライズをいずる
Find me over and over, delivering surprises!
いつかアイドルとは
What is an idol, after all?
時にヤザとか顔が決まりと誰かが言ってたけど 思い通りにできないのでね
Someone said rules like looks and such are set sometimes, but since I can't do it just as expected...
ねぇ奥様 私 から お願い聞いて
Hey everyone, please listen to my request.
そしてそうよ 推し変なんて しないでよね 私 を見て
And that's right, don't ever switch favorites—look at me!
ハッピーラッキーセブン革命いそんで
Hurry up with the happy lucky seven revolution!
みんな！
Everyone!
楽しさに釣られ うっかり探したら
Drawn in by the fun, when I carelessly searched,
知らないあれやこれ 巡り会った
I encountered all sorts of unfamiliar things.
大変な挑戦も のんびり急ぎ足
Even difficult challenges, taking it leisurely yet hurriedly,
支え合って想いを伝説にした
Supporting each other, we turned our feelings into a legend.
見果てぬ国でも 前を向いて
Even in a distant land, looking forward,
小さな星の数につながって
Connecting to the countless tiny stars,
絶えず途切れない 笑い声の中を
Through the unending chorus of laughter,
進んでこう
Let's press onward.
さあ教えて ほら全部
Come on, tell me, hey, all of it!
探検時計の針 ぐるぐる回っても
Even if the clock hands spin round and round on our adventure,
話を聞くよ
I'll listen to your story.
まだまだ終わらない
Still not ending,
この夢がきっと
This dream will surely
永遠に焦る事のない 時を君にくれる
Give you a time that never needs to rush for eternity.
訪れた先で
At the places we visit,
歓声増えてゆく
Cheers keep increasing,
すれ違った風に 聞いたみたい
It's like I heard it in a passing breeze.
そして世界中を 巻き込んで行こう
And let's involve the whole world,
一人また一人 加わった
One by one, more people joined in.
「直感だよ」って 街を探そう
“It's intuition,” let's search the town.
迷子になっても それが楽しみなんだって
Even if we get lost, that's part of the fun,
言っていいんだと
You can say that.
訪れた先で 歓声増えてゆく
At the places we visit, cheers keep increasing,
すれ違った風に 聞いたみたい
It's like I heard it in a passing breeze.
そして世界中を 巻き込んで行こう
And let's involve the whole world,
一人また一人 加わった
One by one, more people joined in.
「直感だよ」って 街を探そう
“It's intuition,” let's search the town.
迷子になっても それが楽しみなんだって
Even if we get lost, that's part of the fun,
言っていいんだよ
You can say that.
探したって どこにいても分からない
Even if we search, no matter where we are...
たくさんの思い出を心に刻み込んで
Engraving countless memories in our hearts,
大切に運び続けるよ
We continue to carry them preciously.
出会えた瞬間に この場所だよって
The moment we met, "this is the place,"
そっと教えて
Softly telling us.
見つけていこう 次は君の番だよって
Let's go find it, "next is your turn,"
そっと手を広げ 伝え続けていこう
Spread your hands softly and keep conveying it.
次は君の番だよって 届くように
So it reaches you, "next is your turn."
奇跡のような
Like a miracle,
キミと作るメモリー
making memories with you,
ギュッと握りしめ 願ったよ
I held you tight and wished.
きっと開花する ワクワクの新芽
Buds of excitement that are sure to bloom.
この場所が初めての 紡ぐ道標
This place is our first guiding path.
ちょっとずつでも 踏み入れてみて
Take steps into it, even if just a little bit.
幸せはすぐ傍にあるものだから
Because happiness is right beside us,
怯えないで 夢中になる
don't be afraid, lose yourself in it.
その力を… for you
That power... for you.
この空に花咲かせてみせるよ
I'll make flowers bloom in this sky.
何よりも強い 生命の息
Stronger than anything, the breath of life.
涙は未来の 味方になるから
Tears will be on the side of the future,
隣で拭いてあげる
so I'll wipe them away beside you.
小さな幸せが積もる未来へ
Toward a future where small happiness accumulates.
La la… 口ずさむ安らぎは
La la... the humming peace
足跡が語る 証の結晶で
is the crystallized proof spoken by our footprints.
次はキミが居るから
Next time, you will be there,
希望は無限大ね
so hope is infinite.
一歩ずつから 始めてみるよ
Let's start taking it one step at a time.
一緒に過ごして 宝物より尊い
Spending time together is more precious than treasure.
夢の続きを 叶えて行こう
Let's continue making our dreams come true,
伝えて行こう… with you
let's convey it... with you.
(I) 散らばった
(I) Scattered
(You) 刻のカケラ
(You) fragments of time.
たとえチグハグだって かき集めれば
Even if they're mismatched, if we gather them up,
ほら 新しいセカイ
look, a new world
開くはずだから
is bound to open.
今日も明日も “ありがとう” 歌っていくよ
Today and tomorrow, I'll sing "thank you."
鮮やかな花を咲かすために
In order to make vibrant flowers bloom,
大空へ満開にしてみせるよ
I'll make them burst into full bloom in the open sky.
何よりも強い 生命の息
Stronger than anything, the breath of life.
涙は巡って 味方になるから
Tears will come around and be on our side,
隣で拭いてあげる
so I'll wipe them away beside you.
小さな幸せが積もる未来へ
Toward a future where small happiness accumulates.
奇跡のような
Like a miracle,
キミと作るメモリー
making memories with you,
ギュッと握りしめ 願ったよ
I held you tight and wished.
きっと開花する ワクワクの新芽
Buds of excitement that are sure to bloom.
この場所が初めての 紡ぐ道標
This place is our first guiding path.
ちょっとずつでも 踏み入れてみて
Take steps into it, even if just a little bit.
幸せはすぐ傍にあるものだから
Because happiness is right beside us,
怯えないで 夢中になる
don't be afraid, lose yourself in it.
その力を… for you
That power... for you.
この空に花咲かせてみせるよ
I'll make flowers bloom in this sky.
何よりも強い 生命の息
Stronger than anything, the breath of life.
涙は未来の 味方になるから
Tears will be on the side of the future,
隣で拭いてあげる
so I'll wipe them away beside you.
小さな幸せが積もる未来へ
Toward a future where small happiness accumulates.
La la… 口ずさむ安らぎは
La la... the humming peace
足跡が語る 証の結晶で
is the crystallized proof spoken by our footprints.
次はキミが居るから
Next time, you will be there,
希望は無限大ね
so hope is infinite.
一歩ずつから 始めてみるよ
Let's start taking it one step at a time.
一緒に過ごして 宝物より尊い
Spending time together is more precious than treasure.
夢の続きを 叶えて行こう
Let's continue making our dreams come true,
伝えて行こう… with you
let's convey it... with you.
(I) 散らばった
(I) Scattered
(You) 刻のカケラ
(You) fragments of time.
たとえチグハグだって かき集めれば
Even if they're mismatched, if we gather them up,
ほら 新しいセカイ
look, a new world
開くはずだから
is bound to open.
今日も明日も “ありがとう” 歌っていくよ
Today and tomorrow, I'll sing "thank you."
鮮やかな花を咲かすために
In order to make vibrant flowers bloom,
大空へ満開にしてみせるよ
I'll make them burst into full bloom in the open sky.
何よりも強い 生命の息
Stronger than anything, the breath of life.
涙は巡って 味方になるから
Tears will come around and be on our side,
隣で拭いてあげる
so I'll wipe them away beside you.
小さな幸せが積もる未来へ
Toward a future where small happiness accumulates.
奇跡のような
Like a miracle,
キミと作るメモリー
making memories with you,
ギュッと握りしめ 願ったよ
I held you tight and wished.
きっと開花する ワクワクの新芽
Buds of excitement that are sure to bloom.
この場所が初めての 紡ぐ道標
This place is our first guiding path.
ちょっとずつでも 踏み入れてみて
Take steps into it, even if just a little bit.
幸せはすぐ傍にあるものだから
Because happiness is right beside us,
怯えないで 夢中になる
don't be afraid, lose yourself in it.
その力を… for you
That power... for you.
この空に花咲かせてみせるよ
I'll make flowers bloom in this sky.
何よりも強い 生命の息
Stronger than anything, the breath of life.
涙は未来の 味方になるから
Tears will be on the side of the future,
隣で拭いてあげる
so I'll wipe them away beside you.
小さな幸せが積もる未来へ
Toward a future where small happiness accumulates.
奇跡のような
Like a miracle,
キミと作るメモリー
making memories with you,
ギュッと握りしめ 願ったよ
I held you tight and wished.
きっと開花する ワクワクの新芽
Buds of excitement that are sure to bloom.
おはよう！ あたしに今日もご挨拶？
Good morning! Are you greeting me today too?
手遅れ？ うそ！ もうこんな時間？
Too late? No way! Is it already this time?
ベッドから出る予定あるのに
Even though I planned to get out of bed,
すぐに支度をしなきゃ
I need to get ready right away.
行ってきます！ 慌てて飛び出して
I'm off! I rushed out in a panic
気付く ここじゃない
and realized... this isn't it!
心の準備できてないの！
My heart isn't ready yet!
トラブルばっか 転んで起きての毎日で
Troubles keep happening, falling and getting back up every day.
なんでも思い通りとか そんな美味しい話はないけど
Things don't always go my way, there's no such easy deal,
心の曇り空を 晴らす合言葉を唱えてほら
but recite the magic words to clear up the cloudy sky in your heart.
ほら 快晴でしょう ずっと
Look, it's clear skies, forever.
みんなに届けたい 歌もダンスも元気も
I want to deliver to everyone, song, dance, and energy.
きっと同じ空の下 笑顔も分け合えるよ
Surely, under the same sky, we can share smiles too.
ちょっと 疲れちゃう時も 涙が出そうな時も
Even when I get a little tired, even when tears are about to fall,
いつもの魔法のことば
saying the usual magical words,
セラセラセラの中から さあ 削れそれを！
from the murmuring stream... come on, carve it out!
みんなご苦労様 今日も一日がんばろ
Good job everyone, let's do our best today too.
カメラにマイクに 衣装準備OK？
Camera, mic, costume preparation OK?
お水もちゃんとうるし 備えあれば憂いなしで
Water is ready too, because being prepared prevents sorrow.
それでは何をしようかな おとなに雑談に あーほら膨らめ
Well then, what should we do today? Adult chats, ah look, expand!
みんなと笑い合わせば 明日も晴れ晴れだ
If we laugh together, tomorrow will be clear and bright too.
よっしゃ！ 快晴でしょう ずっと
Alright! It's clear skies, forever.
ほっとため息こぼして 夜空を見上げたら
Letting out a sigh, when I looked up at the night sky,
ぽっと満天の星たちが キラキラ瞬いてた
suddenly, a million stars were twinkling brightly.
ずっと追いかけ続けたい どんなに高い夢でも
I want to keep chasing it forever, no matter how high the dream,
もっと勇気触れ沸いて 心までかけてゆこう
courage wells up even more, let's run all the way.
そっと背中を押ような 温もりに包まれたなら
If wrapped in a warmth that gently pushes my back,
いつまでも止まらないよ 今日も明日もずっと
it will never stop, today and tomorrow and forever.
セラセラセラの中から さあ 削れそれを！
From the murmuring stream... come on, carve it out!
本日はお寒い中、ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much for coming out in the cold today.
みんな来れた？ あ、来れてるからいるの分かる... あの、ちゃんと安全に来れましたか？
Did everyone make it? Ah, since you're here I can tell... um, did you all make it here safely?
えー、今回のライブは私のライブ史上最大規模ということで、
Um, this live concert is my largest-scale live ever,
すごい大きな会場で、あの、ハッシュタグとかも見てたんだけど、
so it's in a huge venue. I was looking at hashtags and stuff, and...
「でかっ！」「でかいな、すごいな」って書いてる人がいっぱいで、
a lot of people were writing 'It's huge!' and 'So big, amazing.'
私も「でかいな、すごいな」と思いながら見てました。
I was watching thinking 'It's huge, amazing' too.
リハーサルの時は、「ここ、ここにいっぱいそらともさん来るね」って言われて、
During rehearsals, they told me 'Lots of Soratomos are going to come right here,'
「え、誰もいないじゃん！誰もいないよ！」っていう会話をしながら、とても楽しくやっておりました。
and having conversations like 'Eh, nobody's here! Nobody's here!', I had a lot of fun doing it.
でもみんないるね、ありがとう！
But everyone is here, thank you!
というわけで、今日、初めてライブだよって人！
So, for today, anyone who is experiencing my live for the very first time?
現地自体初めてだよって人！
Anyone attending a live venue for the very first time?
頑張って、あの、手振るだけでいいからね。
Do your best, um, waving your hands is enough.
あの、おーなーのーこー！
Um, girls!
声出してくれてありがとう！聞こえた。
Thank you for raising your voices! I heard you.
海外から来てる人！
People coming from overseas!
え、これってあれ、ペンライトとかできるのかな？あ、できないのかな？え？できるのかな？
Um, can you do penlights and stuff for this? Ah, can you not? Eh? Can you?
こちらのひと、あかー！
Over here, red!
こちらのひとは、あー！
Over here, ah!
まんなかは、きいろー！
In the middle, yellow!
わっすごーい！
Whoa!
Amazing!
キレイだねー！
こんな感じでですね、
今日はペンライトでも遊べちゃうということで、
ぜひぜひみんなでも楽しんでいきましょう！
今日はみんなも主役だよ！
え、なんでない？
あみだ可愛い、ありがとう。
もうちょっと飲む？
ねえ、ねえ、ねえ！
すぐお水だって分かったじゃん。
後ろ見たからー。
ありがとー！
さ、というわけでね、
今日はいかがだったでしょうかとはいかないので！
始まったばかり！
なんですが、
なんと！
もう言っていいのかな？
YouTubeの配信は
ここまでなんです。
始まったばかり！
えー！
でもさ、続き見たい人は、
どこだ？ここ、ここ、ここ？
ここらへんに、あの、チケットとか、買う、
買うっていう言い方あれだ、見に来てねー！
チカチカしとる、すごい。
というわけで、先に行どんどん行ってみましょうか！
盛り上がれますかー！
楽しんでいってよー！
それじゃあ、盛り上がっていこうよー！
"nande anata ni wa dekinai no?" nantesa
"Why can't you do it?" you say,
kage guchi iware tari akire rare tari
backbiting and being dumbfounded,
冒頭無料配信はこちらで終了です。
The free broadcast has ended here.